A Guide to the Middagh-Farrar Family Papers, 1824-1901
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Middagh-Farrar Family Papers, 1824-1901
The Library of Virginia
43506
.45 cu. ft.
Philip Perkinson.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased.
Biographical Information
Daniel Middagh (ca. 1778-1853) married Elizabeth Gregory in 1813. They resided in Mecklenburg County, Virginia, where he was a lawyer. Their daughter Georgianna Caroline Middagh (b. ca. 1815) married Dr. Joseph C. Farrar (ca. 1812-1878). Their daughter Maria E. Farrar (1836-1912) married William A. Pace (b. 1831). They resided in Petersburg, Virignia.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1824-1901, of the Middagh and Farrar families of Mecklenburg County, Virginia, most notably Daniel Middagh (ca. 1778-1853), and his son Dr. Joseph C. Farrar (ca. 1812-1878). Includes accounts and receipts, correspondence, estate papers of William H. Byassee (ca. 1808-1859), guardianship papers of the orphans of James Whittemore, papers regarding the sales of the property of Edwin Binford (1812-1884) and John J. Bowen, school compositions, tax tickets, and other items.
The bulk of the correspondence dates from 1848 to 1859. There are letters written to Maria Farrar (1836-1912) from her parents and a former teacher while she was away at school in Lunenburg County, and letters written by her while she was attending Warrenton Female Institute. There are also letters written by her when she was living in Petersburg following her marriage to William A. Pace (b. 1831). Topics covered include her studies, attending camp meetings, family news, and the health and death of their son Daniel Middagh Pace (1855-1857). There is also a notable letter on Reconstruction written in 1867 to Dr. Farrar.
Other items in the collection include agreements, clippings, court papers, fee bills, orders for payment or goods, poetry, promissory notes, recipes, and slave hire bonds.
Contents List
- Accounts and Receipts, 1828-1829. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1830-1839. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1840-1849. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1850-1859. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1860-1869. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1870-1879. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1887, 1896, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Agreements. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "At Home" Announcement - Abner G. and Susie E. Butterworth Wedding, Petersburg, 11 February 1874. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Book and Tract Society - Methodist Episcopal Church, South, 1859. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Clippings. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1827-1859 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1860-1901 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Court Papers. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Deed, 1828. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Estate of William Byassee. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Fee Bills, 1837-1861. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Guardianship of the Orphans of James Whittemore. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Orders for Payment or Goods. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Poetry. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Promissory Notes. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Recipes. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Sale of the Property of Edwin Binford, 1838. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Sale of the Property of John J. Bowen, 1849. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- School Compositions. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Slave Hire Bonds, 1824, 1862. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Speech re: Tariff, 1845? (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1838-1876. (Box 1, Folder 28)